Eesheepal Singh

Front-end Developer | https://portfolio-2024-eeshee-singh.vercel.app/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eesheepal-singh-80057b204/ | https://github.com/eesheesingh | singheeshee@gmail.com | +(91) 8169499331

OBJECTIVE

I'm a front-end developer with an experience of 3+ years, I specialize in creating responsive, user-friendly interfaces using modern stack like ReactJS, NextJS, ViteJS etc. My aim is to building seamless, with better attention to detail in design and functionality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer Jan 2024 – Ongoing

HailGro Tech Solutions - React.js, JS, Vite.js, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Next.js, RESTful API, SignalR

- Building top-notch dashboards and websites with React, Vite, and Next.js. Our team crafts dynamic digital solutions that enhance user experiences and drive business growth.
 - 1. **Copartner**: Main contribution for building Copartner.in, building copartner dashboards along with integration of real-time chat functionalities for users to instantly connect with experts, ensuring seamless communication and enhanced user experience.

Front-end Developer Nov 2023 – Jan 2024

Primite Marketing - WordPress, React.js, JS, Vite.js, Node.js, Tailwind CSS

* Contributed to WordPress website creation and maintenance, specializing in theme customization, plugin integration, and content management to improve user experience. Additionally, participated in coding and developing web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript throughout the development lifecycle.

WordPress Developer Aug 2023 – Nov 2023

TrainerGoesOnline - WordPress, WooCommerce, Elementor, Divi, HTML, CSS, JS, Node.js, React.js

* Engaged with clients to understand their design needs, conducted assessments of their websites for improvements, and utilized WordPress tools to create tailored, visually appealing, and functional websites.

Web Developer Oct 2022 – June 2023

Highkey - Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, Next.js

- * Designed and implemented an efficient order management system along with maintaining order tracking, processing, and success.
- * Developed and maintained product pages using Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB along with integrated payment gateways (PhonePe and RazorPay) into e-commerce platform.

Front-end Web Developer

April 2022 - Aug 2022

Tesla Digital LLP - WordPress, WooCommerce, Elementor, PHP

* Collaborated with clients to identify their design requirements, evaluated their websites for enhancements, and leveraged WordPress tools to develop customized, visually attractive, and user-friendly websites.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Java

Frameworks: Express, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Libraries : React.js, Vue.js, Vite.js, Next.js

Databases : MongoDB, Firebase, Node.js

Cloud : AWS, Google Cloud

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, GitHub, Figma, Webflow, Balsamiq, WordPress

Copartner

React.is, Tailwind CSS, RestfulAPI

Source Code

* In this fast-paced world of stock trading, having the right tools and insights can make all the difference between success and missed opportunities. That is where our platform comes in, especially designed to empower traders of all levels with the resources they need to thrive in the market.

Affiliate Partner Dashboard - Copartner

React, Tailwind CSS, Axios, Swagger, RestfulAPI

Source Code

* Dashboard follows the services for the Research Analysts who want to check daily status of the users who are interested in Stock Trading along with wallet services.

Copartner Chat App

React.js, ASP.NET, SignalR, Axios, RestfulAPI, Node.js, Swagger

Source Code

* This powerful and user-friendly ChatApp uses SignalR to establish real-time web functionality with the ability to connect clients instantly as it becomes available, rather than having the server wait for a client to request new data.

DesiDabba Store

WordPress, Elementor, Woocommerce, Jet Engine

Sn e-commerce website built using PHP, WordPress, Elementor, and WooCommerce. Specializing in offering a wide range of authentic, homemade Indian meals and snacks, the website provides a seamless shopping experience with its user-friendly interface.

EDUCATION

Bennett University
B.Tech Computer Science Engineering
8.4 CGPA

Pace Science Jr. College *Higher Secondary Education*

Mumbai 2019 – 2020

Greater Noida 2020 – 2024

CERTIFICATIONS

- The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp
- Fundamentals of Accelerated Computing with CUDA Python certification on Nvidia
- AWS Academy Graduate AWS Academy Cloud Foundations
- AWS Academy Graduate AWS Academy Cloud Operations
- Natural Language Processing with Classification, Vector Spaces, Probabilistic Models, Sequence Models and Attention Models
- AWS Academy Graduate AWS Academy Machine Learning
- Optimizing a Website for Google Search
- AWS Elastic Beanstalk:Deploy a Python(Flask) Web Application